NWAOBI DANIEL

COMPUTER ENGINEER AND CYBERSECURITY RESEARCHER

CONTACT



+234 802 227 3025



dannychukz15@gmail.com



Benin City, Edo State Nigeria



github.com/CrazyChickenDev



nwaobidaniel.netlify.app

PROFILE

I'm an open-source enthusiast with interests in front-end web development and security. I'm extremely motivated to constantly developing my skills and growing professionally. A penetration tester, red-teamer and self-taught cyber-security researcher that loves being offensive.

SOFT SKILLS

- Conflict Management
- Decision Making
- Integrity
- Communication
- Team Building
- Scheduling
- Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Risk Management

EXPERIENCE

GitHub Campus Expert @ GitHub | University of Benin

OCT 2020 - PRESENT

- Building a strong technical community on my campus by organising events, hackathons, workshops, meetups and the likes
- Creating a community where students can comfortably share their ideas and improve both their tech and soft skills
- Developed and maintained code for event websites primarily using HTML, CSS, Sass and JavaScript
- Interfaced with community individuals with students on a daily basis providing technological expertise

Cyber-Security Intern @ UNiTes

SEPT 2020 - NOV 2020

- Gained simulated experiences in the field of cybersecurity
- Taking up specialization courses in Computer Architecture, Software Engineering and Embedded Systems to broaden skill set and taking up electives in "Cyber Security".
- Manually tested networks, routers, systems and websites in various browsers and mobile devices to ensure cross-browser compatibility, responsiveness and vulnerability
- Built projects related to cybersecurity such as the keyloggers and password list generators

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML	• • • •
CSS	• • • •
Python	• • • •
PHP	• • • •
JavaScript	• • • •
Node.Js	• • • •
Git	• • • •
Linux	• • • •
Bootstrap	• • • •
React	• • • •
Gatsby.Js	• • • •
C++	• • • •

TOOLS

Git | Bash | WordPress | Cisco Packet Tracer | Nmap | Netlify | Heroku | Microsoft Azure | Arduino | MATLAB | MPLAB | Proteus | VsCode Android | Microsoft Windows | Linux

DESIGN

Canva Professional Illustrator Sketch Figma Photoshop Pen + Paper

ren rapei

After Effects

HOBBIES

Watching Movies | Traveling | Dogs Listening to Darknet Diaries Programming | Working with microcontrollers | Embarking on researches | Playing video games Attending Hackathons | Workshops Gadgets

Internet Security Analyst @ Muzzlabs

MAY 2018 - JUNE 2020

- Write modern, performant, maintainable code for a diverse array of client and internal projects
- Work with a variety of different languages, platforms, frameworks, and content management systems such as JavaScript, Node.Js, Gatsby, React, Golang, Canva, Azure, and Netlify
- Communicate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, producers, and clients on a daily basis

Product Lead @ Muzzware

NOV 2019 - PRESENT 2020

- Engineered and maintained major features of muzzware's embedded systems projects remotely
- Proposed and implemented scalable solutions to issues identified with IoT and applications responsible for communicating with microcontrollers
- Interfaced with user experience engineers and other developers to ensure thoughtful and coherent user experiences across project pain-points
- Develop and implement software and hardware solutions based on both company and client requirements

Design Intern @ Muzzlabs

APRIL 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Mentored Co-interns on the fundamentals of Graphics design using tools such as Adobe illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Canva Professional and so on
- Built and designed websites and mobile apps during the internship span.

PROJECTS

Most projects are hosted and showcased on

GitHub

@https://github.com/CrazyChicken Dev

- Password List Generator
- Keylogger
- Portfolio V1
- Portfolio V2
- CPE CGPA Calculator
- CPE Transcript Generator
- Visual Impairment Aid

Co-Founder @ Illusion

FEB 2018 - PRESENT

- Collaborated with a small team of colleagues and friends to spearhead a new brand that makes really awesome gadget customisations in Nigeria
- I design and produce customized gadget skins for clients.
- Effectively makes sure client desires and needs are met in accordance to preferences

EDUCATION

University of Benin

2015/2016 - PRESENT

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer (B.Eng)

Komfota College

FEB 2012 - JULY 2014

Sciences - Senior Secondary School

Ogunlade College

SEPT 2009 - DEC 2011

Junior Secondary School

CERTIFICATIONS/ACHIEVEMENTS

- Winner of the "30-day Microsoft Cloud Skills Challenge" Designing and Implementing an Azure Al Solution (June 2020)
- First Place WINNER Team "TEAM ARTI" at the "Microsoft Build Cloud Skills Challenge" (June 2020)
- **GitHub Campus Expert** for the University of Benin (Oct 2020)
- "Cyber Security Foundation Professional Certificate- CSFPC™" issued by CertiProf
- "ICSI | Certified Network Security Specialist (CNSS)" issued by ICSI,UK (International CyberSecurity Institute)
- **SEPLAT JV** 2020 Scholarship Winner for Students
- "ICSI | Cyber-Security Essentials" issued by ICSI,UK (International CyberSecurity Institute)
- "Introduction to Cybersecurity Certification" issued by Cisco Networking Academy
- "Networking Academy Learn-A-Thon 2021" issued by Cisco
- "Lifelong Learning" issued by CertiProf
- "Virtual Graduate Internship Program (Cyber Security Operation)" issued by UNITeS Cisco Networking Academy